-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案
The Memoris Of Shelock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第七季 第四集
S7E04
红圈会
The Red Circle
Emilia
Emilia.
红圈会奇案
The strange case of the Red Circle
开始于纽约
started in New York
终结于澳大利亚
and ended in the Antipodes.
但首先还是让我说说
But first I should explain
两个名字都以G开头的人
how two men with the initial G
是怎么到伦敦的
came to be in London.
Gennaro是个好汉
Gennaro was the hero,
Black Gorgiano却是个恶棍
Black Gorgiano, the villain
他俩都爱上了Emilia
and both men loved Emilia.
有什么可以帮...
Yes, what can I...
你有房间出租?
You have a room to let?
你瞧 我没有...
Well you see I don't...
是谁呀 Albert?
Who is it, Albert?
是我妻子 平常都是她来掌管这些事
The wife, she usually sees to this, you see.
亲爱的 是个访客
A visitor my dear,
想租个房间
wanting a room.
好了 Albert
All right, Albert,
回你的"造船室"吧
you go into your boat building.
你需要什么 先生?
Now, sir, what do you require?
是只过一个晚上呢
Is it a room for the night,
还是长住?
or for a longer stay?
这么说吧 Warren太太
Well, Mrs. Warren,
我看不出有什么特别的理由 让你觉得不安
I cannot think you have any particular reason for uneasiness
你也注意到了我还有其他事要忙
and you note I have other things to engage me.
福尔摩斯 一个房客
Holmes, the matter of a lodger
在他的房间里待上一个星期也不露面
remaining unseen in his room for more than a week
难免引人好奇
is surely of some passing interest.
换了是我 房东几个星期也不会看到我
If I were a lodger she wouldn't see me for weeks on end.
这没有让你不安吧 Hudson太太?
That doesn't trouble you, does it Mrs. Hudson?
我没什么不安的
Nothing troubles me
只要是有你 福尔摩斯先生
where you're concerned, Mr. Holmes.
但你还记得么
But if you remember
一年前 你就接过Warren太太的 一个房客的案子
you arranged an affair for a lodger of Mrs. Warren's a year ago.
是的 你接过 先生
Yes, you did, sir,
一个意大利绅士 Firmani先生
an Italian gentleman, Mr. Firmani.
Enrico Firmani
Enrico Firmani.
Firmani先生不厌其烦地 说着你的好 先生
Mr. Firmani never stopped talking of your kindness, sir.
你怎么样打破黑暗带来光明
How you brought light into the darkness.
那是个瓦格纳之夜
It was a Wagner night I think.
让我们听听这个房客的事吧
Let us hear about this lodger.
它吓着我了 福尔摩斯先生
It frightens me, Mr. Holmes.
吓的我没法睡觉
I can't sleep for fright
听着他的脚步声从这到那
hearing his footsteps moving here and moving there
从早到晚一刻不停
from early morning to late at night
却从来见不到他 哪怕是一眼
and I never, never catch so much as a glimpse of him.
Warren先生也像我一样紧张
Mr. Warren is as nervous as I am.
那家伙在逃避什么呢 福尔摩斯先生?
What's the fellow hiding from, Mr. Holmes?
他干过什么?
What has he done?
你知道除了那个女仆
You see except for the maid
家里就剩下她跟那个房客了
she's all alone in the house with him.
不 我受不了了
No, I can't stand it.
我的神经承受不住了
My, nerves can't stand it.
华生 看看怎么回事
Watson, cope.
Hudson太太 拿嗅盐来 要是你有的话
Smelling salts, Mrs. Hudson, if you have them.
仔细想想 Warren太太
Take time to consider, Mrs. Warren,
最微小的事也可能是最重要的
the smallest point may be the most essential.
他是10天前来的
He came 10 days ago
他向我房租
and he asked me my terms
我就说一星期12先令
so I told him 12 shillings a week.
一间小的起居室和卧室
There's a small sitting room and a bedroom
位于顶楼 里面一切齐备
all complete all at the top of the house
他说愿意付一星期3镑
and he said he'd pay me three pounds a week for it.
3镑?
Three pounds?
是的 先生 一星期3镑
Yes, sir, three pounds a week
但是得遵守他的条件
as long as I kept his terms.
什么条件?
What terms?
嗯 他想要一把房屋的钥匙
Well, he wanted a key to the house.
这没什么 大多数房客都有
That's all right most of my lodgers have them
但他要求完全一个人
but he was to be left entirely to himself
决不能被打扰
and never on any account to be disturbed.
这也没什么奇怪的
Well, there's nothing very wonderful about that.
算不上个理由 可这又是根本没有道理的
Well, not in reason but this is out of all reason.
他住进来有10天了
He's been in there 10 days
不管是早晨 中午还是晚上
morning, noon and night
不论是她 还是Warren先生或女仆
and neither she nor Mr. Warren
都没有看过他 哪怕就一眼
nor the maid has once set eyes on him.
除了刚来的那个晚上
And apart from the first night,
他也从来没有出去过
he's never once gone out.
哦 刚来的晚上他出去过么?
Oh, he did go out on the first night?
是的 出去过
Oh, yes, he did,
他很晚才回来
he returned very late,
我已经睡觉了
I'd gone to bed
是Warren先生看到他的
but Mr. Warren saw him.
他回来时已经过了午夜
It was after midnight he'd come back.
那吃饭怎么办 我肯定他得吃东西
These meals, I mean surely he eats.
他要吃饭时就摇铃
Well he rings when he wants them.
我们把饭放在他门口的椅子上
We put them on a chair outside his door.
要是他还需要些什么的话
If he wants anything else
他就写在一小片纸上
he writes it on a bit of paper,
用铅笔写
this just in pencil,
只有只言片语
just the one word nothing more.
你看看
Here.
早饭时女仆把"每日新闻"报带给他
The maid leaves the Daily Chronicle with him every morning at breakfast.
为什么用印刷体来写?
Why is it printed?
为了隐瞒他的笔迹
Well, to conceal his handwriting.
华生 你有什么推论
Watson, deduce.
我?
Me?
铅笔尖很宽 写起来带点紫色
Well, the pencil is broad tipped and violet tinted.
写的时候...写的时候相当用力
And it's used with, well it's used with considerable pressure
还没写完纸就被划破了
and the paper's been torn off at the side before the printing was done.
你能看到肥皂(soap)的这个S没写完
You can see the S of soap is partly gone.
表明什么?
Suggesting?
匆忙
Haste.
或者是谨慎
Or caution.
说说这个男人的年龄和长相
The man's age and appearance?
他不到30 先生 一身黑衣服
Oh, he's under 30, sir, he's very dark,
中等身材 胡子刮得很干净
middle height, clean-shaven.
说话的口音和Firmani先生很像
Oh, has an accent like Mr. Firmani.
当然 他没有名字?
Of course no name?
没有 先生
No, sir.
没有信件或者访客
No letters or callers.
一个都没有 先生
None, sir.
他的行李呢?
His luggage?
上面有没有签条?
Labels?
或者贴纸?
Stickers?
"白色之星"号
White Star.
十天前
Ten days ago.
从纽约来
New York.
我想我们还是等等
I think that we must wait
直到有更多的线索
until we have a little more material.
二位请便吧
Please vanish both of you.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes.
噢 谢谢你 医生
Oh, thank you, Doctor.
交给我吧 Hudson太太
Leave it to me, Mrs. Hudson.
你得承认 福尔摩斯 这事还是有点意思的
You must admit, Holmes, there are some points of interest.
只有一点 房间里的人
Only that the man in the rooms
可能和订房间的人不是同一个人了
may not be the one who engaged them.
对啊 当然 我怎么没有想到这一点
Yes, of course, I hadn't thought of that.
在订了房间后他立刻就走了
And he went out immediately after taking the rooms
直到午夜才回来
and returned at midnight.
为什么要换人呢?
Why a substitution?
值得为此
Well, opens up a pleasurable feel
展开一番推理
for intelligent speculation
有一条调查的线索
and there is one line of investigation.
Warren太太的前房客
Mrs. Warren's former lodger.
那不勒斯的Enrico Firmani
Enrico Firmani of Naples.
他在皇家歌剧院的后台工作
He works backstage at the Royal Opera House.
我曾帮他找到过失散的至亲
I helped him find a close relative once.
很简单的案子
A simple matter.
Catchpole街37号
37 Catchpole Street.
你补充了些东西?
You added something?
对那些需要帮助的同乡来说 他是一个朋友
A friend to his fellow countrymen in need.
你是不是认为
Do you suppose
他向他需要帮助的同乡
he could've recommended his former lodgings
推荐了他的前房东?
to a fellow countryman in need?
很有可能
Possibly.
但这解释不了房客的举动
Well, it doesn't explain the lodge's behavior.
举动?
Behavior?
什么举动?
What behavior?
你怎么知道这儿的?
How do you know this address?
从福尔摩斯先生那里
Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
他总是保留着他过去委托人的相关记录
He always keeps a record of his past clients.
要是福尔摩斯要问我的话
But if Holmes has something to ask
为什么他不亲自来
why does he not come himself,
为什么派你来 华生医生?
why send you, Dr. Watson?
我偶尔也自己行动
Well, I do on occasion act for myself.
恐怕我帮不了你
Well, I cannot help you I'm afraid.
我对Warren太太的这个房客一无所知
I know nothing of this lodger of Mrs. Warren's.
他是不是你的一个同乡
Is he perhaps a fellow countryman of yours
刚从美国来 需要帮助?
recently arrived from America in need of help?
那你告诉福尔摩斯我就在这里 如果他需要我的话
Then tell him I'm here if he needs me.
只能说这么多了
That is all I can say.
失陪了
Excuse me,
("纽约时报" 意大利商人命丧布鲁克林)
The New Nork
现在我得去工作了
I must go to work now.
可能是Warren太太需要帮助
It may be that Mrs. Warren needs help.
这个男人在打扰她的家庭
The man is disturbing her household.
为什么 他做了什么了?
Why, what does he do to them?
这个案子更主要是关于他没有做什么
Well, it's more a case of what he doesn't do.
他从早到晚从不露面
He doesn't appear from dawn till dusk.
他的饮食留在门外
He has his meals on a tray left outside the door.
如果他是一个亡命之徒
If he's a fugitive from justice
我们应该把他交给警察
we should turn him over to the police.
警察?
Police?
不 不
No, no.
再见 妈妈
Caio Mama.
如果有什么问题的话
If there is a problem,
福尔摩斯知道在哪里找我
Holmes knows where to find me
在剧院 别来这里
at the theatre not here,
别再来这里了 医生 你听明白了么?
never here Doctor, do you understand?
在这行当 你树了不少敌人吧
You have enemies in your line of work.
每个人都有敌人 不管他们是干什么的
Everyone has enemies whatever they do,
真实的生活就是这样
is that not true of life.
但有些人冒的风险更高
But some are more at risk than others
由于他们的信念
with their beliefs
和他们的勇气
and their courage.
我做我该做的 医生
I do what I do, Doctor,
别要求我做一个圣徒
don't make me out to be a saint.
现在请容我失陪了
Now please excuse me.
Signor Zamba 是纽约的主要水果出口公司
Signor Zamba, senior partner in the firm of Castallote and Zamba,
Castallote & Zamba公司的高级合伙人
chief fruit importers of New York
最近在他家公寓前的台阶上被刺杀
was stabbed repeatedly on the steps of his mansion.
这事发生在8周之前
Now this is dated eight weeks ago.
平克顿侦探事务所的侦探Rimmer
Detective Rimmer of the Pinkerton Agency,
Abe Rimmer
Abe Rimmer.
在犯罪现场表示
Said at the scene of the slaying
这件事是那不勒斯的帮会所为
we believe this is the work of a Neapolitan society
其与烧炭党联合后 以红圈会闻名于世
allied to the old Carbonari known as the Red Circle.
全欧洲都知道
Famous throughout Europe
现在在布鲁克林也发展了一个分支
a branch is now being planted in Brooklyn.
侦探们地怀疑一个叫Giuseppe Gorgiano的人
Detectives are anxious to question a Giuseppe Gorgiano.
Firmani可能还隐瞒了什么事
Now, Firmani was hiding something else.
我说不出来这种感觉
I can't describe the feeling
但那还有一个老妇人 我推测是他的母亲
but there was an old woman who I took to be his mother.
他的母亲?
His mother?
你去他的家里了?
You went to his home?
是的
Yes.
那张写满悲伤和秘密的脸
A face full of sorrow and secrets.
你帮助的就是这个人么 福尔摩斯?
Is this the person that you helped, Holmes?
如果你对我隐瞒了什么
If you're holding something back
我希望你能告诉我
I should like you to tell me.
你去他的家里
By going to his home
可能会给Firmani带来死亡的威胁
you may have put Firmani's life in danger.
什么?
What?
他为那些在伦敦的意大利人提供庇护
He's a point of refuge for the Italian community in London,
像是灯塔发出来的光
a beacon of light if you will
在这张罪恶的黑网中
in a dark web of devilry.
红圈会
The Red Circle.
天呐
God.
是这个Gorgiano么?
And this Gorgiano?
Black Gorgiano
Black Gorgiano,
有死神之称
he's earned the name of death,
在南意大利和更远地方
La Morte in Southern Italy and far beyond.
是很有名的杀手
He's red up to the elbows in murder.
有没有可能这个Black Gorgiano
Is it possible that this Black Gorgiano
就是Warren太太的房客?
is the man at Mr. Warren's?
不是的 但有着某种联系
No, but there may be some connection.
华生 我们有事要做了
Watson, we have work to do.
去歌剧院
The opera house.
然后在查令街十字
And then Charing Cross
给我的朋友Abe Rimmer发一封电报
to send a telegram to my friend Abe Rimmer.
非常好 Laven小姐
Wonderful, Miss. Laven,
请再来一遍
just once more, please.
Enrico Firmani
Enrico Firmani.
你一直和我作对
You have been troublesome to me for a long time.
现在你帮我
But now you help me
就饶你一条命
in return for your life,
Gennaro Lucca
Gennaro Lucca,
你把他藏到哪去了?
where are you hiding him?
你到底说还是不说 Enrico?
Will you tell me, Enrico?
这里不容许通行
Nobody's allowed in here.
哦 是你 福尔摩斯先生
Oh, it's you, Mr. Holmes.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
Hawkins 你怎么到这来了?
Hawkins, what brings you here?
我想和你来的理由一样
Same thing that brings you I expect.
我无法想象您这么快就接手这个案子
How you got onto it so fast I can't imagine.
不同的线索
Different threads
把我们引到了同一场纷争里
leading up to the same tangle.
我们是来找Enrico Firmani的
We've come to see Enrico Firmani.
他已经死了
But Firmani's dead.
在还不到2小时前 在这里被人割断了喉咙
He was found with his throat cut less than two hours ago up here.
恐怕凶手已经逃得无影无踪了
Murderer got clean away I'm afraid.
华生
Watson.
你说中了 福尔摩斯
You're right, Holmes,
我今早不该去找他的
I should not have gone this morning.
或许能救他一命
Might have saved a life.
我想这不该怪罪于你
I don't think you can blame yourself for that.
才子娇娃同归泉壤 正像扫烟囱人一样
Golden boys and girls all must as chimneysweeps come to dust.
(莎士比亚 此处用朱生豪译文)
一个人孤身来到伦敦
A person arrives alone in London.
他去找Firmani寻求帮助
He seeks help from Firmani,
他的同乡为了安全起见
his fellow countryman
安排他住在Warren太太的公寓里
who places him for safety in Mrs. Warren's lodgings.
紧接着Firmani被谋杀了
And then Firmani is murdered
是因为不肯说出这个藏身之处
rather than give away the hiding place.
不 不
No, no.
还不能肯定这一点
Of that we can't be sure.
那是谁杀了他呢?
But who killed him?
Gorgiano?
Gorgiano在英国么?
Is Gorgiano in England?
他想把这个房客怎么样?
What does he want with this lodger?
公寓房间里的那个人 完全孤立 很危险
The person in that room is entirely alone and at risk,
甚至写一封信都可能被截获
I mean even a letter might be intercepted.
那么他是怎么收到外面的消息?
How does a message reach him from the outside?
除非是通过那个最有价值的猎场
Except by that most valuable hunting ground
甚至对那些不同寻常的学者来说
ever given to the student of the unusual.
报上的广告栏
Agony columns.
我们只需要把注意力放在
We need only concern ourselves
过去两周的
with the Daily Chronicle.
每日新闻报上
For the past two weeks,
我们的房客每天早饭后
which our lodger collects every morning
都要翻阅它的
after his breakfast.
哦 天呐
Oh, dear me,
好一个喊叫和呻吟的大合唱
what a chorus of cries and groans.
好一堆怪事奇闻的大杂烩
What a ragbag of singular happenings.
在王子滑冰俱乐部...
Lady with a feather boa
戴黑色羽毛围巾的女士
at Prince's Skating Club.
福尔摩斯 听听这个
Holmes, listen to this,
耐心点 将寻找一种可靠的通信方法
Be patient, will find some means of communications,
目前仍用此栏 G
meanwhile this column G.
你能再沿着这条线索找下去吗?
Can you pick up a trace again?
噢 有了
Ah, here we are.
正在做有效安排
I'm making successful arrangements,
请耐心谨慎
patience and prudence,
乌云就会散去 G
the clouds will pass G.
哦 没有了
No, nothing.
在这 道路已清除
Here, here, the path is clearing.
如有机会 当发信号
If I find chance to signal message
记住说定的暗号
remember code as agreed,
这是两天前的
that's two days ago.
Hudson太太?
Mrs. Hudson?
有什么事 福尔摩斯先生?
What is it, Mr. Holmes?
我正洗窗帘呢
I'm washing curtains.
请找一下昨天和今天的每日新闻报
The Daily Chronicle yesterday and today,
如果你乐意的话
if you'd be so kind.
耐心谨慎
Patience and prudence.
现在这事终于有点眉目了
Now the affair begins to grow more intelligible.
我找到了
I've found it.
带门廊和黑门的房子 第二层
House with porch and black door, first floor,
窗户右边 黄昏后 G
window right, after dusk, G.
你看
There you are.
G... Black Gorgiano
G, Black Gorgiano.
可能会是个陷阱 来引那个人出去?
Could it be a trap, to draw the person out?
不大可能
Unlikely.
我们是不是该把已经知道的 红圈会的事告诉警察
Well should we not tell the police what we know about the Red Circle?
告诉警察?
Tell the police,
他们手头的事就够他们受的了
they find it difficult enough to deal with the facts
别用我们的想法来让他们更困惑
without confusing them with our suppositions.
听听这个
Oh, listen to this,
毫无动机的谋杀
motiveless murder.
根据对Hawkins警督的采访 真是
According to Inspector Hawkins, really.
福尔摩斯先生 医生 你最好快一点
Mr. Holmes, Doctor, you must come quickly,
有人被绑架了
there's been a kidnapping.
应该交给警察 福尔摩斯先生
This is a police matter, Mr. Holmes.
我要把那个房客赶出去
I'm throwing that lodger out.
我该去和他直说了
I'd have gone straight up and told him so...
但她认为应该
But she thought it only right
先征求您的意见 福尔摩斯先生
to ask your opinion first, Mr. Holmes.
请泡一壶茶 Hudson太太
A large pot of tea please, Mrs. Hudson.
我实在是没有耐心了 这已经连累到我丈夫了
I'm at the end of my patience when it comes to knocking my old man about.
谁要伤害他?
Who knocked him about?
我要是知道就好了
I wish I knew that.
事情是今早发生的 先生
It happened this morning, sir.
Warren先生
Mr. Warren
是Tottenham宫廷路上 Norton & Waylight公司的计时员
he's a timekeeper at Norton & Waylight's on Tottenham Court Road.
他必须在早晨七点钟以前出门
He has to leave the house before seven in the morning.
要是我能和他谈谈会大有帮助
It would greatly help me if I could speak to him myself.
好的
All right.
小心点 福尔摩斯 他心脏不太好
Take care, Holmes, his heart.
你来说说吧 Warren先生
Can you speak, Mr. Warren?
我出门还没有走上10步
Well, I hadn't gone ten paces
后面就来了两个人
before two men crept up behind me.
拿大衣蒙住了他的头
And threw a coat over his head,
把他塞到了马车里
bundled him into cab
开了一段路后 在Hampstead荒地把他扔了出来
and drove off and shot him out on Hampstead Heath.
Hampstead荒地
Hampstead Heath.
真可怕 你看到什么了么?
Dreadful, what did you observe?
我乘公共汽车回的家
I took a bus home.
在这之前呢
Before the bus,
那些人
these men,
你有没有看清他们的长相?
did you observe their appearance?
没有 先生 好像是变魔术一样 我被抓进去
No, sir, I was picked up as if by magic
又被扔出来
and dropped as if by magic.
车里至少有3个人
Three of them at least was in on it,
也可能是4个
maybe four.
你听见他们说话了么?
Did you hear them talk?
其中一个用意大利语赌咒发誓
One of them swore some oaths in Italian.
钱可不是万能的
Money is not everything.
我今天就要把他给赶出去 就在今天
I'll have him out of here before the day is done.
我想见见你的这个房客
I should like to meet this lodger of yours.
他什么时候吃午饭?
What time does he take his lunch?
一点整
One o'clock sharp.
有没有什么地方能让我们藏起来?
Is there anywhere where we might conceal ourselves?
有的 楼上有个储藏室
Yes, there's a box room upstairs.
有没有一面大镜子?
Is there a looking glass?
有的 在房间外楼梯平台那的抽屉里有一面
Yes, there's one on the chest of drawers outside on the landing.
好极了 来吧 华生
Excellent, come, Watson.
那我该怎么办?
What about me, then?
我们有40分钟
We've got forty minutes.
很明显他的敌人们弄错了
It's clear now that his enemies mistook their man.
想都不敢想 要是他们抓到他会怎么样
What they would've done if they'd got him bears no thinking.
可他们没有
But they didn't.
你看到了么?
Do you see what I see?
一个带门廊和黑门的房子
A house with a porch and black door.
有一个房间出租
With a room to let
这样G就可以进到那里去
to which G could have access.
福尔摩斯 我觉得我们应该通知苏格兰场
Holmes, I feel very strongly that we should inform Scotland Yard.
还不是时候
Not yet.
我们在监视
We are on watch,
或许也在被监视
and may be being watched.
让我们看看房子后面有什么吧
Let's see what lies behind these lodgings.
他感觉怎么样?
How's he feeling?
噢 他很好
Oh, he's all right.
他就是喜欢小题大做
He just likes a fuss made of him.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
锁上你的门
Bolt your door.
在我们回来前别让任何人进来
And let no one in until we return.
你看到他了么?
Did you see him?
Warren太太 请相信我
Mrs. Warren, trust me.
我不知道他什么时候回来
I don't know when he's coming back.
他给了我一些钱
He gave me some money
之后就再没有见过他
and I haven't seen him since.
你说是一个外国绅士
A foreign gentlemen, you say.
肯定是 但我不介意他是外国人
Definitely and I don't care for foreigners.
哦 是吗
Oh really.
要是你想租的话 先生
So if you want it gentlemen,
我们可以签个合同
I'm sure we can come to an arrangement.
等你看完了以后 我在大厅等你 先生
I'll be in the hall sir, when you've finished.
谢谢
Thank you.
这什么都没有
Nothing in here.
好极了
Perfect.
看 华生
Look, Watson,
公寓2楼的窗户里
the first floor window of the lodgings,
住着我们焦虑的女士
our agitated lady.
只需要再等几个小时
Only a few more hours to wait
就会发信号
before the signal.
黄昏之后 G
After dusk, G.
一切都符合为爱私奔的条件
It has all the makings of some love escapade.
爱?
Love?
爱或许是这件事的根源
Love may be at the root of it
但她的脸
but her face,
噢 华生 她的脸
oh, Watson her face
上面写满了对生活的忧虑
She fears for her life,
我想有一对夫妇
I consider a couple,
来伦敦避难
seek refuge in London
为了躲避某种威胁
from some instant and terrible fear.
丈夫为了最大限度保证妻子的安全
The man desires her utmost safety
而采用如此原始的方式
and arranges to communicate
来进行联络
in such original fashion
甚至是女房东 也不知道房客已经换人了
for not even the landlady knows of the substitution.
字条是用印刷体写的 以防有人通过笔迹认出来
And there's printed messages to prevent the fact that she's a woman
房客是一个女人
being revealed by her handwriting.
看
Look.
蜡烛和火柴
A candle and matches,
他们的信号
Their signal.
现在其实没这个必要
But there's no need for this now surely,
就不能直接让他们见面么?
can't we just simply bring them together?
你能保证我们能一直保护他们
And guarantee that we'd protect them forever
免遭红圈会的毒手么?
from the Red Circle?
不能
No.
我们得让他们继续这么下去
We must let them play this thing out.
我先回贝克街
I must return briefly to Baker Street.
你能不能找个借口留在公寓?
Do you have reason enough to stay in the lodgings?
就说是为了Warren先生的健康
Mr. Warren's health gives me every excuse.
或许我有必要把你的左轮手枪带来
It might be advisable for me to bring back your revolver.
不用 我已经带着了
No need to man, I have it.
好极了
Good, splendid.
我们一小时后见
I'll see you within the hour.
Hawkins 希望到头来有情人终相聚
Hawkins, journey's end with lover's meeting.
我会主持正义的 福尔摩斯先生
I'll do you this justice, Mr. Holmes.
我办案子的时候只要是跟您合作
I was never in a case yet
就没有一次觉的不踏实
I didn't feel stronger for having you on my side.
逃亡的人可能是Gennaro和Emilia Lucca
Fugitives may be Gennaro and Emilia Lucca
如果是这样 那他们处境危险
if so in grave danger,
很需要我们协助
expect agent imminently.
祝好 署名Abe Rimmer
Regards, Abe Rimmer.
他已经来了
The agent's here,
今天早晨从纽约来的
he arrived from New York this morning.
名字叫Leverton
His name is Leverton.
我听说过这个名字
Leverton I know of him.
他一直在追捕Black Gorgiano
The man he's after is Black Gorgiano,
红圈会的头目
leader of the Red Circle.
我们是不是这一次领先你了 福尔摩斯先生?
Do we score over you for once, Mr. Holmes?
你得更努力一点了
You must give us best some of the time.
我想我们都应该竭尽全力
I think that we should pool our resources.
楼上有人
There's someone up there.
Warren太太
Mrs Warren.
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
让楼下保持安静
Keep the peace downstairs.
我得和Senora Lucca说几句话
I must have a word with Senora Lucca.
Senora Lucca
Senora Lucca,
我是歇洛克・福尔摩斯
its Sherlock Holmes.
我必须和你谈谈
I must speak to you.
哦 不
Oh no.
你丈夫Gennaro和你都会安全的
Your husband Gennaro, will be safe, and so will you
如果你愿意接受我们的保护
if you will place yourself in our hands.
苏格兰场在监视这所房子
Scotland Yard is watching the house
Leverton先生也在从纽约赶来
and Mr. Leverton is on his way from New York.
Leverton先生?
Mr. Leverton?
我们不会让你受到任何伤害的
We shall not let any harm come to you.
请让我进来
Please let me in.
好么
Please.
我再也不上去了
I'm not going up there again.
绝不
Never.
亲爱的 别说傻话
Oh don't be silly dear,
别傻了
don't be silly.
你听到医生的话了
You know what the doctor said,
是一只猫在抓
it was just a cat scratching.
不 不是的 天花板都被掀起来了
No, it wasn't, it lifted.
Hudson太太 你能给Vera倒杯茶么?
Mrs. Hudson, would you make Vera a cup of tea, please?
这屋子里发生什么了?
What is going on in this house?
吵吵嚷嚷 灯也不亮
Noises, lights going off,
我快要死了
it'll be the death of me.
噢 天呐
Oh my god.
我出生在那不勒斯附近的Posillipo
I was born in Posillipo near Naples.
我父亲是名首席律师
My father was chief lawyer.
Gennaro没有钱 也没有地位
Gennaro had no money and no position,
虽然没有这些 但是他英俊 有活力
nothing but his beauty, his strength and energy.
我父亲不同意我们结婚
My father forbade the match
我们就私奔
and we run away.
在巴里结了婚
We were married in Bari.
我卖掉了首饰当路费 来到了美国
I sold my jewels to bring us to America.
一开始命运向我们微笑
Fortune smiled at first,
Gennaro从几个暴徒手中
Gennaro saved a rich Italian
救下了一个富有的意大利人
from some ruffians in the Bowery.
名叫Signor Castallote
He was Signor Castallote
经营Castallote&Zamba水果出口公司
of Castallote and Zamba the fruit importers.
Gennaro与他情同父子
Gennaro became like a son to him.
告诉我们这个访客的情况
Tell me about this visitor,
这个你们从Posillipo来的朋友
this friend of your husbands from Posillipo?
噢 他不是朋友
Oh, is no friend.
Gennaro有一天把他带回家来
Gennaro brought him home one day.
他们是在街上偶遇的
They had met in the street.
以后他就经常来
He came again and again.
他大谈什么政治和社会问题
He talked and raved about politics and social questions
以及他的打算 还挥舞着他巨大的手臂
and what he meant to do, whirling his great arm.
他的声音在我们的小房子里 听起来就像是打雷
His voice was like thunder in our little house.
那你的丈夫呢?
And your husband?
他坐在那 脸色苍白 无精打采
He sat pale and listless.
一开始我以为他是不喜欢
At first I thought it was dislike
后来我才明白
but then I understood
是一种深藏的恐惧
it was a deep secret fear.
我恳求他出于对我的爱
I implored him out of love for me,
出于我们相濡以沫的感情
by all we held dear
告诉我为什么这个人 能给他带来这么大的阴影
to tell me why this man overshadowed him.
在他年少不羁的时代
In his wild, young days
全世界好像都跟他过不去
when all the world seemed against him
他就加入了一个兄弟会
he had joined a brotherhood,
El Chicaroso
红圈会
the Red Circle.
他以为它的目的仅仅是
He thought its purpose
反对生活中的不公正
was to put right the injustice of life.
一旦你发了那个可怕的誓
Once you've taken its dreadful oath.
告诉我关于
Tell me about you,
你和Gorgiano
and Gorgiano.
我早就注意到了 当他来找我们时
I had noticed for some time when he came to us
他总是盯着我看
his eyes were always turned upon me
那眼睛真可怕
his terrible glaring eyes.
有一天晚上
And one evening,
他说我唤醒了他所谓的爱
I had awakened what he called love in him.
-Emilia 我的唯一 -那是一种野兽般的爱
-Emilia, mio solo grande. -It was the love of a brut,
野蛮粗俗
a savage.
几天以后
A few days later,
红圈会有一个会议
there was a Red Circle meeting.
他们勒索Signor Castallote
Signor Castallote had been approached for money
却遭到了拒绝
and had refused them.
于是他们计划杀了他
Now they planned to kill him,
通过抽签来决定谁动手
they drew lots.
这是早就安排好的
It was fixed.
因为我拒绝了Gorgiano 他要报复
It was Gorgiano's revenge for my rejecting him.
我在这世上
My dearest friend,
最好的朋友
in all the world.
然后你们一起去了警察局?
And then you both went to the police?
我一个人去的
I went alone.
真勇敢
That was brave.
就算是 可这有什么用呢?
Yes, but what has it done?
我们被迫逃走 我们的朋友还是难逃一死
They got us away but friends still die.
我们永远逃不出那野兽的控制 永远
We shall never be rid of that beast, never
现在你得走了
and now you must go.
我已经说的太多了
I've said too much,
已经违背了对我丈夫的许诺
I've broken my promise to my husband,
快走吧 求你了
go please, go.
Enrico会感到欣慰的
Enrico would have wished it.
开始新的生活吧
Go sail to a new life.
Gracias
Gracias.
他不能整夜待在这里
He can't stay here all night.
要是有必要 他会的 是么 医生?
Well if he has to won't you, Doctor?
好吧 那样的话 我们来玩会惠斯特纸牌吧
Well, in that case I wouldn't mind a game of whist.
你玩惠斯特纸牌么 医生?
Do you play whist, Doctor?
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
Emilia
Emilia.
Emilia 我的爱
Emilia, mi amore.
Hawkins
Hawkins.
我已经安排了人监视 福尔摩斯先生
I've set my men on watch, Mr. Holmes.
你在期待什么?
What are you expecting to happen?
不止一次 侦查行动的作用有限
Well, there are times when the art of detection is of little use.
得等待那些无法预知的事发生
We must wait upon the unpredictable.
我也有这样的经验
I've had some experience of that in my time.
我可以说 我们要等的是Signora Lucca的丈夫
I can say only that we are expecting Signora Lucca's husband.
你得放他过去
You must let him pass.
你的人不要干扰他
Your men must not distract him.
-他们知道的 -很好
They know that. Fine.
-那我们要抓的凶手呢? -噢 他就在附近
-And our murderer? -Oh, he is about.
某个地方
Somewhere,
等待机会下手
waiting his chance.
美国的Leverton给了我一份详尽的描述
I have a good description from the American Leverton,
我们都准备好了
we'll be ready.
看
Look.
华生
Watson.
Signora Lucca
Signora Lucca,
你必须告诉我暗号
you must give me the signal.
走开 我再不会相信你了
Go away, I don't trust you.
除了我丈夫 我谁也不信
I trust no one but my husband.
非常感谢你 医生
I'm obliged to you, Doctor.
最好不要动弹
The main thing is just to keep this still as possible.
好的
Fine.
-福尔摩斯先生 -福尔摩斯
-Mr. Holmes. -Holmes.
这是平克顿侦探事务所的 Leverton先生
This is Mr. Leverton of the Pinkerton Agency.
破获长岛山洞奇案的Leverton么
Leverton, of the Long Island Cave mystery
很荣幸见到你
I'm honored to meet you.
是我的荣幸 先生
The honor is mine, sir.
好吧
Well, well, well.
很可惜这幅模样见你
I'm sorry we had to meet like this.
你很勇敢
You're a brave man,
我看到你在屋顶
I saw you on the roof.
当你毕生时间都用来追踪这件事的时候
When you're on the trail of a lifetime, Mr. Holmes,
你也会把个人安全
you put all thoughts of personal safety
置之度外的 福尔摩斯先生
out of your mind.
我想那混蛋跑掉了
The brute got away I suppose?
是的 但他会回来的
Yes, but he'll be back soon.
这房子里有
There's something in this house
他梦寐以求的
that he wants badly.
噢 是的 我知道
Oh, yes, I know.
谢谢你 医生 我很好 真的很好
Thank you, Doctor, I'm fine, just fine.
楼上的女士安全么?
Is the lady upstairs, safe?
是的 但不再相信任何人
Yes, but trusting no one.
所以我们必须等待
And so we must wait
他丈夫发出的暗号
for her husband's signal.
什么暗号 福尔摩斯先生?
What signal, Mr. Holmes?
Leverton 灯
Leverton, the lamp.
这么说Gennaro Lucca就在那儿?
So Gennaro Lucca is over there now?
还没有 但我想他会来的
Not yet but he will be I hope.
当我到伦敦的时候 我也找不到Lucca
I couldn't find Lucca when I got to London.
我们通过Enrico Firmani进行联系
My contact was Enrico Firmani
但那家伙找到了他
but the brute reached him first
在杀死他之前肯定也让他开口了
and he must have made him talk before killing him.
我们是不是该上楼去看看Lucca夫人?
Shall we not go upstairs to reassure Mrs. Lucca?
她不会让我们进到房间里去的 华生
She won't admit us, Watson.
她现在只听她丈夫的
She'll only answer to her husband.
噢 看哪 是Hawkins
Oh, look, Hawkins
不是很显眼
not too conspicuous.
对 Hawkins警督 他看来来很能干
Yes, Inspector Hawkins, he seems an able fellow.
是苏格兰场最好的一个
One of Scotland Yard's finest.
业务熟练
He knows his business.
先生们
Gentlemen,
Gennaro Lucca刚刚进来
Gennaro Lucca has just gone in.
目前为止一切顺利
So far so good.
夫人是在红圈会计划要杀掉Castallote
Mrs. Lucca came to us
那天晚上来找我们的
the night the Red Circle planned to kill Castallote.
他们已经杀掉了他的合伙人Zamba
They'd already murdered his partner Zamba.
我们设法把团伙成员一网打尽
We managed to round up most of the gang
但那个Black Gorgiano漏网了
but Black Gorgiano slipped the net.
一听说他来英国
When we heard he'd left for England,
我也就尽快赶来了
I followed after him fast as I could.
我和苏格兰场取得了联系
I got in touch with Scotland Yard
他却没有踪影了
but he'd gone to ground.
开始发出暗号了 是什么意思?
There's a single light, what does it mean?
两个灯光
Two lights.
-消失了 -不 又有了
-Gone. -No, no, there it is again.
缓慢的闪三下
Three lights measured slow.
他要说什么 到底什么意思?
What's he saying, what does it mean?
没什么意思
Nothing,
没什么
nothing.
但他下一步肯定是要确认一下
But his next actions must confirm it.
他肯定是来这里等她
He must come here to collect her.
又消失了
It's gone.
收到消息了
The message received.
什么消息?
But what message?
Gennaro
Gennaro.
我最好的朋友
My dearest friend in all the world,
和兄弟会的叛徒
and betrayer of the brotherhood.
这不是在发信号 有个人跟他在一起
There's no message there's somebody with him.
华生?
Watson?
你听到了么 福尔摩斯?
Did you hear that, Holmes?
是的 危险
Yeah, danger.
天哪 看 她跑出来了 跑到街上了
My God, look she's out there on the street.
华生
Watson.
Hawkins 你要抓的人在那
Hawkins Your murderer is up there.
不可能 这只有一个入口
Impossible, there's only one entrance.
等一下 他是我的人 Hawkins
Just a minute he's mine, Hawkins,
-我来负责 -不 你不能 先生
-I'll take responsibility. -No you won't sir,
伦敦的事由伦敦警方负责
London dangers are up to the London force.
Gennaro
Gennaro.
Emilia
Emilia.
华生 带他们离开这个恐怖的地方
Watson, take them away from this horror.
请把船票给我 先生
I'll take those tickets, sir.
求求你 我们的船黎明时起锚
Please, our ship sales at dawn.
你打算把它怎么办 警督?
What are you going to do with him, Inspector?
他将被逮捕 并以谋杀Gorgiano的罪名被指控
He'll be arrested and tried for the murder of Gorgiano,
法律就是法律
that is the law.
我不知道你们英国的法律会怎么对他
Well, I don't know what your British law may be
但我想要是在纽约
but I guess that in New York,
这位女士的丈夫会收到很多的感谢信
this lady's husband will receive a pretty general vote of thanks.
这世上没有哪一个法官 会给这个男人判刑
There's not a judge on earth that will condemn this man.
我想Lucca夫妇没有什么好担心的
I don't think Mr. And Mrs. Lucca have too much to fear
但我们还是得遵守法律程序
but we have to go through the procedures.
带他们下楼
Take them downstairs.
要是你一个人在这里 福尔摩斯先生
No doubt if you'd been here on your own, Mr. Holmes,
你会有不同的解决方法吧
you'd have found a different solution.
我们生活在法律之下 警督
The law is what we live with, Inspector.
但有的时候正义更难实现
Justice is sometimes harder to achieve.
我还是不明白 你是怎么一开始
What I still don't understand is how you came to be mixed up
就卷到这件事里来的
in all this in the first place.
晚安警督
Good night, Inspector.
晚安 福尔摩斯先生
Good night, Mr. Holmes.
看来英国的司法 对这对年轻夫妇很友善
English justice looked kindly on the young couple
不久 他们就去了澳大利亚
and soon afterwards they left for Australia.
在那里终于摆脱了红圈会的威胁
There they found a new and happier life
过着新的幸福生活
free from the threat of the Red Circle.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.com